For most of this semester,I've said absolutely nothing in tutorials.
在这个学期的多数时间里，我在课上都没有说过话。
But recently,I've been trying to speak up more and I just jump in, and I've noticed an interesting thing.
但是最近我试着多发表意见，我投入到讨论中并发现了一件有趣的事情。
I've noticed that if they thought my point was interesting or new, then the next time they actually asked for my opinion,
我发现如果他们认为我的观点很有趣或新颖，下一次他们就会询问我的意见，
and then it was much easier for me to be part of the discussion.
这就使我顺利的加入到讨论中去。
That's great,Hiroko! I hope that happens for me next semester - I'll have to work hard to find some interesting points.
太好了，Hiroko！希望下学期我也能这样。我得努力学习找出一些有趣的观点。
What helped you to find these ideas?
我得努力学习找出一些有趣的观点。
I think that one thing that helped me with this was the reading.
我认为是读书帮了我。
I've had to do so much reading this semester just to help me make sense of the lectures.
这学期我不得不读很多的书，以帮我理解讲课的内容。
At first I couldn't understand what the lecturers were talking about, so I had to turn to the books and journals.
起初，我不明白老师在讲什么，所以我不得不看书和期刊。
Every night I read for hours,using the lists of references that were given, and I made pages of notes.
每晚我都照着参考书单读几个小时的书，我还做了很多页的笔记。
At breakfast,I read and read my notes again.
早餐时，我一遍遍地读我的笔记。
This habit has helped me to follow the ideas in the lectures, and it's also given me some ideas to use in the tutorials.
这个习惯帮我跟上了讲课的思路，并且在讨论课上带给我许多启发。
But i did so much reading anyway - I don't think there's any time left over for anything extra.
但是我也做了许多阅读，我认为没有什么时间做这些额外的事情。
My reading speed is still quite slow, though I'm much better at dealing with vocabulary than I used to be.
我的读书速度还是很慢，尽管我现在比过去在处理词汇上要好很多。